hey everyone thanks for listening to The
Grow Your Life podcast my name is
Jeremiah Krakowski and on this podcast I
help you grow your life your business
make more money impact more lives
and change the world now today I want to
talk about those of you that need help a
little bit with your time optimization
your time management I have a number of
courses in our membership program where
we go over this and how you can optimize
this we just had a conversation today
with our high level coaching group about
how to do this when you know that you
need to do something in your business
but you're procrastinating and how to
manage all the different things that you
have going on
and this is a principle that I have
learned and applied and developed over
the last couple of years that I think
can really positively affect you to
create the results that you're looking
for in your business
it's not as much much about
what do you put in your day planner how
you map out your to-do list
or strategies of like you know write
this out five times do this Etc you're
not going to get any of that from me
what you're going to get from me is more
strategies that I've applied over the
years
to get more done with last time
because I believe that time is a
construct that we have control over and
we can either be imprisoned to
time controlling us or we can have
control over time
so that's one of the first beliefs that
we have to challenge is that
the time that we have is finite and that
it is in control of us and that we're a
victim to it
or that we have plenty of time to
accomplish all the things that we want
to accomplish in our life and and I want
you to take on the latter perspective of
that you do have plenty of time you
might be sitting here over the age of 60
years old feeling like you have no idea
what you're talking about Jeremiah
I understand that maybe your your
perspective is that
um
you know I challenge you that you can
get a lot more accomplished in the next
five years and you have the last 60 and
I've worked with a lot of people that
are over the age of 70 and even 80 years
old that have accomplished more in three
to five years than most people do in
their lifetimes and so I've seen that
happen and I know that and I've worked
with thousands of people
to to give me this perspective
what we have to do is we have to stop
operating number one out of a scarcity
mindset I have lack I don't have enough
I can't accomplish what I need to with
what I have
realize that that's just not simply true
at all
that we do have enough with the time
that we're given
and that when we go into an abundance
mindset of believing that we have enough
some amazing things start to happen now
some actual practical strategies of this
are
take a look at in your life
what are areas where
you have obligations this is one of the
first areas that I tell people to look
at what are obligations that you're
required to do every single day
and realize that those are actually
choices
that's that's the first shift
is realizing that the things that you
believe that you are obligated to do
every single day are actually just
choices
that's it
and and this is a paradigm shift for
some people
you know I've been cussed out for saying
this to some people as well
I understand again
we all got different situations
we all have choices to make every single
day
and when we let our obligations Define
what we have the capability of doing in
our lives we now become a victim
to outside circumstances okay so I want
you to shift again out of the victim
scarcity mindset and I want to raise you
up to the higher level
of being able to accomplish
anything
that you go out there and doing
when it comes to your time
you can create time time
is not as finite as we see it we're able
to mold it
and bend it to our will
make it submit to us and that's one of
the biggest things that most people
don't realize because they've never been
taught how to do so they've just been
taught that you have you know we all
have the same 24 hours in a day and most
of us fill our day up with things that
we have to do
and we're also not taking care of
ourselves that's another aspect if you
find maybe you lack time are you getting
enough sleep are you are you eating
right
are you eating in a way that spikes your
glucose or blood sugar
and now and now causes you to have less
energy are you not taking care of
yourself that's one of the first things
that we want to explore is if you have a
lack of energy
and you're not getting enough sleep yeah
and by the way you know I have a seven
month old baby I know what it's like to
not get enough sleep
but I also know that when I prioritize
it in the days that I need to
it helps me operate at a higher level
in a more optimized way
and so we have to break past all these
excuses see listen if you're listening
to this right now you're five minutes in
and you're just making excuses
I want to shift you out of that
first off
excuse of holism is not
productive Behavior
coming up with reasons why your
situation this doesn't apply to you okay
so let's let's address that first off
and then let's start to look at no
matter what situation we live in in life
no matter what we're going through
realizing
that we get to Define
our day our life
and our future
and it's not defined by outside
circumstances if you're living your life
right now where your life is defined by
everything outside of you it's because
you've
you've actually put things in order and
placed things in that way and you've
chosen to give up the authority
and the autonomy and the agency of your
life to everything else around you
so that's one of the first steps is to
take back that agency
to take back
that Authority
to where you're no longer
just a victim of
what everybody else tells you that you
should be doing
and this is one of the first things to
look at you know there may be things in
your life right now that you do
maybe even in your business because I I
talk to mentors and coaches and trainers
there's
activities in your business that you're
supposed according to everybody else's
best practices that they say that you
should be doing
and if you only eliminated those things
you would create
openings in your time to be able to
accomplish and to do more things
so just simply realizing that by saying
no
to certain obligations
as painful as it may be
and being willing to open up time
by choosing
to stop doing things even if you feel
you should be doing them see this this
is why most people are not able to be
successful they're unwilling to make the
sacrifices that they need to make when
it comes to
their day their life they're weak their
finances their relationships their time
whatever that is and listen don't
misinterpret me
in the most negative light
to her maybe you assume that I'm saying
to neglect your family and to to
just don't even don't even
fabricate that
false narrative
okay
because I never said any of that at all
but that's where our brains go to that's
where we go to the extreme version to
demonize especially if it violates
everything that we've been taught to do
is oftentimes our brain will go into
the most extreme
version
in order to discredit
what somebody's saying that we know you
know I I guarantee you right now as
you're listening to this you know that
if you stop doing certain things every
single day
you restructured certain things in your
life that you would create the time to
accomplish all the things that you want
to do
so don't let your own brain talk you out
of that
don't let your own
thinking
talk you out of the truth of knowing
that you are in control of what you do
every single day you're not a victim
and that you can choose to move things
around
and boundaries on our time
being willing to say no to things that
might be good
that might even be what we should be
doing that might even have been
obligations by the way what do you do
when you when you change an obligation
when you move an obligation around you
find somebody else to delegate it to
if you have an obligation you find
somebody else to pass it off to
so this is one of the first areas that
we need to grow in
is to learn to delegate things to people
and not feel guilty passing off
activities
to other people
that's one of the first things realizing
that you don't have to be the savior of
the world that does everything for
everybody and that you don't have to be
the one person who shows up that the
buck stops at
when you when we shift our mindset when
we shift our activities
out of
perfectionism
needing to be the one that controls
everything needing to manage other
people's emotions and feelings
and we learn to delegate and we learn to
say no to things that might be good
and we even learn to say you know what
even if I quote unquote should be doing
that I'm going to choose not to with
intention
because I'm prioritizing
what I want that I haven't made space
for in my life and when you actually
make space for
the things that you want to do and that
you want to accomplish
that's where the Beauty and the magic
happens
one of the biggest reasons why people
don't accomplish what they want is they
just don't want it bad enough
they just don't have a desire
to actually go after
the things that they really want you
might be saying Jeremiah you don't know
what you're talking about I want it more
than air or water itself
your actions don't show so otherwise you
would
you would move some things around and I
understand that that might be really
offensive
to you
you might want to challenge why this is
so offensive
why
it's so difficult to hear the truth like
this
and realize that for you to be able to
create the kind of wealth that you want
to create for your family
which we gotta shift out of
operating in the way that we always have
that we've always done one of the worst
things that we can do in life one of the
worst phrases is well that's how it's
always been
that's how we've that's how we've always
done things
sad
when I hear people say that because
they've automatically shut their brain
down to innovation
to ideas
but when you can start to look at and
you have a vision for okay this is the
direction that I'm going in my life and
you start to visualize the best case
scenario and you start to visualize the
the life that you want this is what I've
done in my life this is what has created
in our life we've made over a million
dollars in one year
and prior to that I was an employee
working for other people struggling in
my own personal income struggling with
debt struggling in my relationships and
it all hinged on
what I'm talking about today with you
learning that I don't have to be a
victim to procrastination I don't have
to be a victim to my feelings I don't
have to be a victim to my emotions
I don't have to justify what I do
to anybody
and when you realize that and we step
out of this behavior that we feel like
we have to quote unquote operate in a
realm of what we should do of what we've
always done and we learn to choose let's
just pick one of those items maybe you
don't do it all of it a big clean sweep
of your life activities and habits all
in one day but maybe just one percent
what if you take one percent of your
activities and you shift the priorities
around and then you start making it a
priority to accomplish your business
maybe you start making yourself a
priority maybe start making your
self-care
a priority some people say I don't have
time for self-care I'll tell you
self-care is one of the number one
profit producing activities that you can
possibly do
when we can take care of ourselves
instead of just pouring out
for others
you know there are people that actually
believe that to take care of yourself is
evil
and that to to not give a hundred
percent 110 of yourself for other people
is evil
and I you know I I feel sad for
whoever
psychologically manipulated and lied to
those people to believe that
I used to be one of them
I used to be one of them that believed
that
my Pro my needs didn't matter
my desires didn't matter my priorities
didn't matter
that I didn't matter
and then I was working and struggling
with an uphill battle
trying to accomplish all the dreams and
goals and visions that I had in my life
and all it took was a shift and a focus
to change
what's the priority in my life
and to start to do the things that would
move the needle forward for me even if
it meant stopping doing things that I
was obligated to do and passing them off
to somebody else
stopping doing the things that I quote
unquote should do that were taking more
of my time than
than created a necessary outcome for me
and by choosing to do these hard things
and make those sacrifices and making it
a priority in my business
to create the kind of business that I
want to create the kind of life that I
want to create the kind of marriage kind
of family life the kind of home that I
want we just closed on a home today
that's what shifted everything for me
and that's what's going to shift it for
you it's a choice
we're not a victim
maybe you're still listening to this
right now and you're saying you know
Jeremiah you you don't know my situation
you got no empathy for what I go through
just
just pause that defensiveness for a
moment I did a podcast episode about how
defensiveness is one of the greatest
hindrances to business success
that need to defend ourselves to justify
ourselves to try to prove others wrong
to try to prove that we're right instead
of learning to grow
instead of being willing to say how I've
been doing things up to this moment in
time hasn't been working
let me try something different let me
learn from somebody who has been where
I've been
get mentored and walk down a path I've
been where you've been and I've walked
down the path and I've come out the
other side and I'm here to tell you
it doesn't have to be this way it's all
a choice
one of the greatest things that helped
me in this is when I started working
with a therapist and I started realizing
that I had beliefs in my head beliefs in
my brain that were stopping me based off
of trauma and traumatic experiences that
I was operating from a programming my
brain was literally wired and programmed
against
being successful in business
and I sought out to create the kind of
neural Pathways that I needed to create
to be successful I've seen my mother do
it
firsthand I wondered why I struggled
with it
and I set out on my own journey to not
just you know just because I'm
Sandy krakowski's son
doesn't make me entitled to any level of
success
but realizing truly realizing
that the life that I'm living today was
a result of the choices that I've made
skills that I've gained my ability to
communicate my ability to have tough
conversations my ability to do the hard
things my ability to make the sacrifices
that I've needed to make
and on the other side of that is a life
that I can truly say today
everything that I dreamed of five years
ago
and now I'm in a new season where I'm
passing that on to other people what
have I learned in the last five years
you know in the last five years
um I started this business
struggled to make the kind of Revenue I
wanted to make we made six figures
some of y'all are like I just wish I
could make six figures great I promise
you you can make six figures doing what
I share with you what I'm sharing with
you is what has taken me to even seven
figures and it's working on what's up
here and I'll tell you even that's the
six figure level if you if you get
started and you work on this stuff
initially man I wish I knew this stuff
five years ago
I wish I knew what I just told you five
years ago I probably would have fought
it I probably would have been angry at
it
I probably would have not been happy I
probably would have judged myself in
fact I had people trying to tell me this
stuff five years ago and I was so mad
they don't know what I've been through
they don't know what situation I've gone
through
so I get it I do I really do I get where
most of you have been through those that
are in our coaching program know that
they they know a lot of this stuff that
that y'all are walking through I've
walked through as well
and I've walked through it both in my
own life and with other people I've set
out to to prove these methods to prove
what works and to bring you strategies
that I know will produce results in your
life and if you start to apply this if
you start to
realize that you have control over your
time you have control to create moments
in time for you to accomplish things in
your life that you are not a victim
to everything outside of you
and you can start to move puzzle pieces
around you can start to prioritize
things
and then you can start to do those
priorities
that that's where your dreams will start
to happen
and so I'm excited listen I hope this
has challenged you
maybe it's triggered you maybe you're
going to realize that it might be time
to go talk with a therapist
it might be time to work through some of
those
issues that are limiting you and your
behavior that you're operating in the
same framework which you've always done
for the last five to ten years
and start to move the needle forward for
yourself so that you can make the kind
of money that you want to make the only
reason why anybody listens to my podcast
is because they want to increase their
income
that's it
you can make the hard choices you can
accomplish the things that you want to I
believe in you I know you can
and listen to this episode has impacted
you pass it on to somebody else share it
with somebody
I think it'll really impact them as well
grow your life everybody
we'll talk soon
[Music]
[Applause]